João Rafael Martins

linkedin.com/in/joaoraf github.com/joaorafaelm joaoraf@me.com +55 41 998693157 Curitiba, Brazil

~

About me

Software developer with over 10 years of experience on ML/AI and web development. Focused in Back-end development, NLP research and tasks such as text classification, controlled text generation, AutoML, xAI and general predictive models.

~

Professional Experience

Python Developer / ML engineer @ Xapo / Remote / 2018 – 2020

Part of the risk and security team responsible to build and maintain the pipeline of all virtual transaction analysis in real time. REST API development and integration with 3rd party APIs using Python and Flask; UI development using React; ETL & Data lake infrastructure; Led the development of the whole AI pipeline, from ETL to real time predictive models and model interpretability;

Technologies used: Jenkins, Hashicorp Vault, AWS products, Python, Flask, React, NPM, Mysql, Docker, Sci-kit learn, TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch, Google Cloud products, New relic etc.

~

Python Developer @ Olist / Remote / 2017 – 2018

Develop and maintain private and open source software. Architect, deploy and monitoring of micro services. Code Review and pair programming. Also involved in the development of predictive models for churn detection, document classification, other data science related projects and natural language processing tasks.

Technologies used: Heroku, AWS products, Python, Django, React, NPM, jQuery, Redis, PostgreSQL, Docker, Sci-kit learn, TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch.

~

Full stack Developer @ SmartGreen / Brazil / 2015 – 2017

Responsible for managing web systems written in Python using the Django Framework, and PHP. Development of high performance and scalable software written in Javascript (NodeJS), Python and Go. In charge of maintaining, creating and optimising front-end components, using technologies such as ES6, React, jQuery and others. Experience with TDD methodology, writing unit, integration and acceptance tests. Also responsible for maintaining CI and CD servers. Creation of native packages (deb and rpm). Use of agile methodologies such as Scrum. Projects involving data analysis for anomaly detection.

Technologies used: Python, NodeJS, Django, React, NPM, jQuery, RabbitMQ, Redis, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Xen, QEMU, Docker, Celery, MQTT, Vagrant, VirtualBox, Sci-kit learn.

~

Web Developer @ AutoGestor / Brazil / 2014 – 2015

Development of web platform using PHP, with own framework, Front-end interfaces using Jade and Handlebars. Creation of REST API, and integration with other platforms, such as Facebook, Mercado Libre, OLX and others. Also responsible for Database administration and maintenance.

Technologies used: PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, HTML, jQuery, CSS, Bootstrap.

~

Full stack developer @ Freelancer / 2009 – 2014

Responsible for the design, layout and coding a websites and systems. Also involved with the maintenance and update of websites. Designed interface prototypes, and software architecture. Building and testing APIs for applications to exchange data.

Technologies used: PHP, Python, MySQL, JavaScript, HTML, jQuery, CSS, Bootstrap.

Education

Languages

 ${\bf English}-Fluent$

Portuguese — *Native*

French — *Basic Level*

Spanish — *Basic Level*

~

Skills

Languages: Python, Go, Ruby, C, PHP, Javascript (ES5, ES6, NodeJS), Java and Elixir. Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, ElasticSearch, RDS, Redis, Memcached, SQLite and Cassandra.

Versioning: *Git and SVN.*

CI and CD: Ansible, Fabric, Native Packages(.deb, .rpm), Jenkins and Gitlab.

Infrastructure tools: Vagrant, Docker, Xen, Kubernetes, Open nebula, AWS, LXC,

and VirtualBox.

Cloud providers: AWS, Azure and Google cloud platform.

Message Queues: Rabbit MQ, SQS, ActiveMQ and Redis.

Other Frameworks and Tools: React, Flux, Angular, Django, Phoenix, Ruby on

Rails, Laravel, Xen Server and Py.test.

Machine Learning frameworks: Sci-kit learn, Tensorflow, Keras, PyTorch.